

Prabhu Vignesh Kumar Rajagopal

CLOUD AND DEVOPS CONSULTANT



CONTACT INFORMATION

www.prabhuvigneshkumar.com

prabhu.vignesh1990@gmail.com

+91 8377003750

8 hireprabhuvignesh

in linkedin.com/in/prabhuvigneshkumar

github.com/prabhuvignesh

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- Completed M.Tech in Computer Science in the year 2014 from SRM University with 86%
- Completed B.E in Electronics in the year 2011 from Gojan Institute with 79%
- Certified EMC Cloud Associate in Cloud Infrastructure and Services.
- Certified Solution Architect By Rackspace CloudU.

CORE QUALIFICATION

- Expertise in maturity assessment in terms of system design, infrastructure and DevOps environment around public and private cloud including AWS, Google Cloud and OpenStack.
- Expertise in As-Is analysis, GAP analysis and report generation to identify rifts in system design, Infrastructure and in DevOps environment to be upgraded in maturity model.
- Expertise in providing infrastructural Automation solution with Configuration Management in Ansible & Chef with Docker and Vagrant.
- Have Experience with Refactoring Monolithic application to MicroServices Application with Docker, Consul, Docker swarm, Kubernetes and REST API along with Enterprise Service Bus (Mulesoft & Dell Boomi).
- Have experience with designing ServerLess Architecture with AWS Lambda and with CRM solutions like Salesforce.
- Have good real-time experience with one of the best DevOps practice - CI/CD with Jenkins and Bamboo with GIT, Gerrit, Infrastructure as code with Terraform and Ansible.
- Expertise in Release Management with creating Release Policy, Planning, Build Configure and Implementation with above skills along with Release Workflow.
- Experienced with Ruby, Ruby on Rails and Python, Django, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, scripting languages including Shell, JavaScript for Linux and Mac platforms

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As an experienced DevOps and Cloud Consultant, I can provide DevOps solutions, Cloud Solutions, Enterprise Design and Integration solutions around the public and private cloud (AWS, Google Cloud and OpenStack). Being a Polymath, I have strong experience in As-Is analysis, Maturity Modeling and GAP analysis to design framework and target operation model in terms of Architectural design and DevOps environment around Public and Private cloud.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

@KPMG.

Role: DevOps Consultant

MULTI NATIONAL FINANCIAL COMPANY - December 2017 - Present

- Conducted maturity assessment and GAP analysis then generated report in terms of system design and infrastructure.
- Provided solution by designing the Infrastructure in AWS for middleware application which integrates Salesforce application & Angular application and created Infrastructure as code from AWS & Terraform to reuse the infrastructure.
- Designed the Delivery pipeline with Jenkins right from creating a
 feature to deploying feature by integrating Version control tool with
 ALM tool. This helps to stay in line with Agile process.
- Created monitoring and analytics platform to ensure "Disaster Prevention and Preparedness.

Role: DevOps Consultant.

MULTI NATIONAL OIL & GAS COMPANY - August 2017 - December 2017

- Conducted As-Is analysis and GAP analysis then generated report in terms of system design and security.
- Provided solution by developing a middleware solution with Enterprise Service Bus to integrate various in-house application and business applications. Integrated applications with open APIs and other business applications.
- Provided solution for maturity in security by developing policy, strategic, tactical and operational information security plans and ensured developed services comply with established SOA governance rules, maturity and monitoring.

Role: DevOps Consultant.

Multi-National Media Company - May 2017 - August 2017

- Conducted As-Is analysis and GAP analysis then generated report in terms of system design and Integrated Agile and DevOps Ecosystem.
- Provided solution to improve in system designing by Transforming and refactoring the Monolithic architecture to MicroServices with containerization and clustering tools like Docker and Consul

•

KEY SKILLS

Cloud Services

- AWS, Google Cloud, IBM Bluemix.
- Openstack

DevOps Ecosystem

- Jenkins, Git, Gerrit, Bamboo.
- Ansible, Chef, Terraform
- Munin, Nagios.

Containers and Clusters

- Docker, Vagrant.
- Consul, Nomad, Docker swarm, Kubernetes.
- Mulesoft, Dell Boomi.

Agile and Tools

- Jira, TFS.
- Scrum and XP.

Programming language and Development Frameworks

- Ruby, Python.
- Ruby on Rails, Django, Flask, Sinatra (MVC).
- Bash, Ruby, JavaScript.
- MySql, PostGres, MongoDB, Sqlite.
- Unix and Windows

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Kudos award from KPMG for Performance
- Raising star award from KPMG for Performance
- Best Performer award from HCL
- 22nd rank in Codewars in 2014 tournament.

INTERESTS

- As part of being a Cloud and DevOps Consultant, I love to do POC and experiment with new techniques and platforms which comply with the latest market needs.
- I love to provide solutions to the business where they stuck or go slow in terms of technology. Since the technology is the backbone of any business, it should be strong enough and I ensure that
- With my hands-on experience in technology and foundation, I am very comfortable to build any solutions regardless of new product or technology.
- As part of Open Source devotee, I keep contributing open source community either by producing a new piece of a component or fixing the most needful component. Same can be seen from my Digital footprint

DIGITAL FOOTPRINTS

- in linkedin.com/in/prabhuvigneshkumar
- github.com/prabhuvignesh
- hub.docker.com/u/vickyrajagopal/
- galaxy.ansible.com/PrabhuVignesh/stackoverflow.com/users/4269160/prabhuvignesh-rajagopal

- Provided solution to improve in Software delivery and release by providing Integrated agile and DevOps ecosystem with building CICD with Jenkins and configuration management with Ansible and integrated Issue and Bug tracker with Agile driven tool like TFS, Remedy and Jira.
- Ensured all application satisfies 'The twelve-factor app' and created a complete prototype to ensure system design the industrial standards and adaptability for new technologies.

Role: DevOps Consultant.

Multi-National Media Company. - November 2016 - April 2017

- Conducted As-Is analysis and GAP analysis then generated report in terms of system design and Infrastructure.
- Provided solution to improve in system design by designing the Service Oriented Architecture with Docker containers and Kubernetes.
- Provided solution to improve in application infrastructure by designing the architecture underlining with MicroServices hosted on AWS and minimized the effort and infrastructural demand with serverless architecture with AWS Lambda.

@HCL

Role: DevOps Engineer

MULTI NATIONAL TRANSPORT COMPANY - April 2016 - November 2016

- To integrate the client's UAT and Production environment, quick containers was needed for Jenkins (DB server, Hadoop clusters).
 Docker containers are Integrated and delivered with Jenkins integration.
- Each and every commit of code and particular time period my Jenkins server will build and integrate the UAT environment and production environment was the on-demand basis.

DevOps Engineer

MULTI NATIONAL TRANSPORT COMPANY - June 2015 - March 2016

- Client requirement is that their production environment should meet High Availability and scalability.
- Created Ansible playbook with dynamic inventory file which dynamically allocates the range of IPs with respect to No of Docker containers has been created. Each task was perfectly separated by role for an easy change.

Role: Developer

HCL Internal Application. - November 2014 - May 2015

Developed an application for stockholders to fill their work progress and generate scores and reports according to that. With the help of 20 and more tightly associated tables in Postgres. With the help of jQuery tools like morris.js and flat.js, achieved Reports and graphs for the dashboard.

Role: Developer

HCL Internal Application. - August 2014 - November 2015

Developed a portal application within a collaborative web application for training and self-development for internal employees. In this PostgreSQL was used within the application and exported Postgres data into MySQL by rake task periodically.

KEY SKILLS

Cloud Services

- AWS, Google Cloud, IBM Bluemix.
- Openstack

DevOps Ecosystem

- Jenkins, Git, Gerrit, Bamboo.
- Ansible, Chef, Terraform
- Munin, Nagios.

Containers and Clusters

- Docker, Vagrant.
- Consul, Nomad, Docker swarm, Kubernetes.
- Mulesoft, Dell Boomi.

Agile and Tools

- Jira, TFS.
- Scrum and XP.

Programming language and Development Frameworks

- Ruby, Python.
- Ruby on Rails, Django, Flask, Sinatra (MVC).
- Bash, Ruby, JavaScript.
- MySql, PostGres, MongoDB, Sqlite.
- Unix and Windows

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Kudos award from KPMG for Performance
- Raising star award from KPMG for Performance
- Best Performer award from HCL
- 22nd rank in Codewars in 2014 tournament.

INTERESTS

- As part of being a Cloud and DevOps Consultant, I love to do POC and experiment with new techniques and platforms which comply with the latest market needs.
- I love to provide solutions to the business where they stuck or go slow in terms of technology. Since the technology is the backbone of any business, it should be strong enough and I ensure that
- With my hands-on experience in technology and foundation, I am very comfortable to build any solutions regardless of new product or technology.
- As part of Open Source devotee, I keep contributing open source community either by producing a new piece of a component or fixing the most needful component. Same can be seen from my Digital footprint

DIGITAL FOOTPRINTS

- in linkedin.com/in/prabhuvigneshkumar
- github.com/prabhuvignesh
- hub.docker.com/u/vickyrajagopal/
- galaxy.ansible.com/PrabhuVignesh/ stackoverflow.com/users/4269160/prabhuvignesh-rajagopal

@Personal Projects

Role: End to End

Musickouty

Social media which provide portal to upload the music file to a playlist which can be shared with friends added within the portal. Uploading music files and login services, Sound Cloud API is used. Separate user relationship modules are maintained for follow and unfollow the users among the portal.

Role: End to End

Robin

Developing Tool called Robin in Ruby on Rails which automates the application build, deploy and code repositories. Git gem was used to create project, branch, commit, pull and push automation through rails. And Build and Deployment on remote machines was automated with Ansible, with the help of ansible-rails gem.